[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
Thank you, Jaguar, but I need
to go back to the mansion
to find out the truth about my mother.
[Ivy] The one who helped Emilia escape
was none other than Jaguar.
-The Ardientes' men!
-[gunshot]
[Julio] Jaguar helped you escape.
You have been working with him all along!
-Get out of my house!
-Papa.
[Julio] And never set foot
in this house again!
[Camia] Diego, this is the day
we've been waiting for.
I will be the governor of this town.
For a new Ardiente!
[Diego] I have a plan.
And in this plan,
my victory will be certain.
We'll just have to blow things up.
[explosion]
[Ivy] Mom, it's Uncle Damian. He escaped.
He was never released from jail.
[Damian] You, Emilia,
are the one responsible
for my brother's death.
I'll make sure you pay for what you did.
[Diego] Julio, your time is up.
I'll make sure that from this day on,
evil will no longer reign in Ardiente.
[woman] Diego's in the lead in
most of the neighborhoods.
This fight isn't over.
Let's all just celebrate, okay?
Batch! Batch! Guys, it's here.
The unofficial tally from city hall.
Diego's ahead by 30,000 votes.
[cheering]
-[man] Bro.
-Hold on, hold on.
That's not all,
because the towns
that haven't been tallied
are the towns of our supporters.
-Wow.
-So, this is a sure win!
[cheering]
[Marlon] It's a sure win, Batch.
I'm sure, Diego. You've won.
Congratulations!
[cheering]
[reporter] Let's head over
to Poblacion Ardiente.
Diego Torillo has a lead
over Congressman Julio Ardiente
in the votes.
Wow.
It looks like the bastard,
Diego, is going to win.
Boo, Papa! You deserve that.
For once, you'll know
the feeling of being a loser.
[ominous music playing]
-This is our victory.
-[phone rings]
[indistinct chatter]
Excuse me, Auntie.
[Loring] Are you okay?
[phone ringing]
Diego.
-Julio.
-[chuckles]
Until now, I'm still not used
to you not calling me Grandpa.
What do you want?
You want me to tell you straight?
I would like you to concede.
Concede?
You want me to give up?
Around 11 in the evening…
you can clear out your things
from the polling precinct.
Afterward…
Tell the people that you're conceding
the governorship to your grandpa.
Because the truth is…
you love me,
and you have complete faith
in my leadership.
And most of all…
it's important to you
that we all get along.
Because, at the end of it all,
we're family, aren't we?
I won't do that.
It's time for the lives of the people
you've been stepping on to get better.
So, Julio, say goodbye to your throne.
[phone rings]
Ivy.
Diego. Did Julio call you?
Yes, Ivy, he did.
He wanted me to concede,
but there's nothing he can do
because the counting is almost over.
[scoffs] Ivy.
Ivy, we're going to win.
You're right, but we need to
know what Julio's next plan is.
Yes.
But, Ivy…
Ivy, I want to thank you.
Congrats, Governor.
You're the reason I won this.
This is the victory
we've all been fighting for.
So, thank you.
Thank you for everything.
I have to go.
[singsongs] Papa is a big loser.
Big, big, loser.
Hi, Miss Beautiful.
Don't come near me. Stay there.
Don't come any closer.
Stay there! [shrieks]
-Give me your cell phone.
-You can't escape.
[shrieks] Let go of me!
[groans]
Don't fight back.
-[smack]
-[groans]
Let's go.
[Emilia] Let go of me!
[man 1] Over there.
Here.
Get your hands off me.
-Let go…
-Over there, dude.
[groans]
-You filthy animals!
-[laughing]
Don't come near me!
I'll have you killed.
He called you filthy, dude.
Have your way with her!
-This is nice, dude.
-Stay away from me.
I'll finally taste a rich girl.
-Hurry up!
-Please! Don't come near me!
Nothing personal, Miss Beautiful.
[grunts]
Just relax!
[shrieking]
Just relax, Miss Beautiful.
-Let go of me!
-[laughter]
She's like a wild horse!
-[groaning]
-[smack]
-Go on.
-I told you to relax.
[Emilia groans]
-No. No…
-Why are you so stubborn?
Have us killed, huh? Yeah, right!
-[laughing]
-No. No. No.
[Emilia grunts]
No matter what you do,
no one will hear you.
-[shrieking]
-Remember that, Miss Beautiful.
[Emilia groaning]
[man 1] Just relax.
-[Emilia panting]
-[man 1] You smell so good.
[man 1] So good!
-[grunts]
-[groans]
She stabbed me! She stabbed me!
I'm giving you my permission.
Do it, Martel.
[upbeat music playing]
[chuckles lightly]
Cheers, my grandson.
Cheers to this huge victory.
I promise you…
I will win this fight.
Ivy.
Cheers!
Congressman, Diego is leading--
I don't give a hoot about what they say.
I will win.
Arnaldo will win.
The Ardientes always win.
Miss Ivy Aguas…
I don't care if I have to bomb a truck,
a precinct,
or even a whole building.
I will do all that to ensure my victory.
Remember that.
Whatever it takes
to keep my grandson happy.
And to keep this family name on top.
My grandson…
Victory is yours.
[dramatic music playing]
Arnaldo?
Yes! I am! I am Lily Cruz!
I am Lily Cruz! I am!
Arnaldo.
Arnaldo, my grandson.
Arnaldo?
[dramatic music playing]
[wheezing]
[Julio] Yes? Yes?
What is it? What is it?!
-[groaning]
-Tell me!
[groaning]
-Arnaldo?
-[groaning]
Friends! Here it is!
The partial unofficial tally.
Diego got 725,364 votes!
-[cheering]
-Okay, okay. Wait, wait, wait.
Guess how many votes Ardiente got.
-What?
-He only got 421,000 votes!
[cheering]
Friends! We only have
one neighborhood left.
You basically won, Batch!
[cheering]
-Go, Diego!
-Batch.
One neighborhood left!
You've surely won this!
-Batch. It's a win.
-We won.
-Diego…
-The new governor!
We succeeded. You succeeded.
-[cheering]
-Auntie… Auntie…
[Pandoy] Yes! Yes!
Auntie, this is everyone's victory.
Long live Governor Diego Torillo!
-Governor Diego!
[cheering]
[man] Long live!
-[cheering continues]
-[man] To Diego!
Uh…
[Arnaldo groaning]
-Arnaldo.
-Nurse!
Arnaldo, what's wrong?
Tell me so I can help you.
-Tell me! Tell me! Tell me!
-Nurse! Nurse!
Tell me. What is it? I… I can help you.
[groaning continues]
[nurse] Relax, sir.
[cheering]
[Camia] Cheers!
-[cheering]
-[indistinct chatter]
[line rings]
[phone rings]
-[tense music playing]
-[ringing continues]
[line ringing]
-One more. Just a bit more.
-One more town.
[screams]
[shrieks]
-[man] Hey, what happened?
-[indistinct chatter]
-Why'd it stop working?
-I don't know.
Calm down, guys. It's all right.
Listen, everyone! Wait! Wait!
Everyone!
Citizens of Ardiente, let's not panic.
Please, stay calm. And no pushing.
Let's not get anyone hurt.
Let's make this a peaceful election.
Diego, 90% of Poblacion Ardiente
has just lost electricity.
-Oh, no.
-No…
I bet this is part
of Julio Ardiente's plan
to sabotage the election once again.
What are we going to do, Diego?
How can we stop Julio
from sabotaging the election?
-[Camia] Geez!
-We don't have control
over the system's data.
But we can ask for
additional poll watchers.
Tell them to make sure the votes
won't be tampered with.
Mister Danny, Mister Jun,
please tell our poll watchers
to be on their guard.
-Hurry! Now!
-Come on! Hurry!
Take care.
[Arnaldo groaning]
Hon, what's happening?
[groaning]
Honey.
Give him some sedatives.
It's okay, hon.
It's okay, Arnaldo. I'm here.
[cries]
-Your grandpa is here.
-[groans]
-Hon.
-Arnaldo. Arnaldo!
I'm here. I'm here.
[Arnaldo crying]
Excuse me. Let me handle this.
Hon, it's okay.
I'm here, hon.
Nurse, what… what happened? Is he okay?
[tense music playing]
Sorry, I can't get any updates
because of the power outage.
When can they restore the power supply?
They don't know yet.
But no matter how long this takes,
I'm sure you'll still win, Diego.
You already had a huge lead
even before the power went out.
Besides, the remaining votes
are from Diego's bailiwick.
-There's no way Julio will win.
-[Pandoy] Remember, dear.
We're facing Julio Ardiente.
Anything can still happen.
-Don't be such a pessimist.
-I'm just stating facts.
As long as no one cheats,
it'll be Diego's win for sure.
I've lived here all my life, remember?
I know what that Julio is capable of.
Uncle, calm down. Please.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia panting]
-[shrieks]
-Jaguar ordered us to get you.
[gunshots]
Oh!
-The power's back!
-They're working again.
-Batch, please ask for updates.
-Okay. I'll be right back.
-All right, he's on his way.
-Thank goodness.
Doc, can you please explain
what's happening to Arnaldo?
Sometimes, this happens to patients
who've woken up from a coma.
-[doctor] So, we don't…
-[Jose] Congressman.
[voices drop out]
Sir, there's an update on the votes.
-[tense music playing]
-[no audible dialogue]
[Julio] Your news…
just made my day.
[no audible dialogue]
-Batch. Batch.
-This is something else.
-The results just came out.
-How was it?
Batch, come on.
What happened? Did Diego win?
-Batch?
-Julio Ardiente's winning.
-Huh?
-What?
That can't be true.
-Julio cheated!
-[Julio's supporters cheer]
-You cheaters!
-Auntie Camia.
-You sabotaged the election!
-[Julio's supporters cheer]
-Cheaters!
-[Pandoy] This isn't over!
We know what the truth is!
[unintelligible]
[man] This isn't over!
Don't rejoice just yet!
[unintelligible]
[Jose] Congressman. Everybody!
We are leading by 151,560 votes
over Diego Torillo.
That means we've won. Viva Ardiente!
[cheering]
[dramatic music playing]
Raise your voices, everyone.
Shout louder until we can
all be heard by our enemies.
So they'll know that we remain the rulers
of Poblacion Ardiente. Viva Ardiente!
[all] Viva Ardiente!
[cheering]
[dramatic music playing]
Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, who won for president?
My candidate! Who else?
[man 1] Yeah, right. What did
he ever do for the country?
He's all talk, no action.
That's our country for you.
We never learn.
We bring you the latest partial
and unofficial vote count
covering 99% of polling precincts
for the gubernatorial election
in the province of Ardiente.
The competition
in this province is fierce.
952,896 votes have been counted
for Julio Ardiente,
while 801,336 votes have been
counted for Diego Torillo.
The people have spoken!
We now have a new governor.
The pillar of the entire
province of Ardiente,
the father of the people, Julio Ardiente!
[supporters] Long live!
-Viva Ardiente!
[unsettling music playing]
You lying, cheating, old man.
You abandoned me.
I hate you. You should've just let me die.
I'd like to extend
my gratitude to you all.
Thank you for trusting me,
for voting for me,
and for helping me land this victory.
Again, please accept my deepest thanks.
And, as early as now,
I'm telling you, I cannot
govern this land alone.
And that's why, this early on,
I'm calling on each
and every one of you
to help me with my term
so that we can restore the former beauty
and splendor of Poblacion Ardiente.
Let us take our land
back from our enemies!
[cheering]
I'd also like to dedicate this victory…
to my one and only grandson, Arnaldo!
Arnaldo, who, truthfully,
should be the one standing here right now.
The one standing here
in my place as governor,
as governor of the people.
He'd be here if not for
those hooligans he fell victim to.
He's now in critical condition.
Remember this.
We're going to take back
our town from the hands of those
who plan to take it for themselves.
And my new slogan is:
To a new Ardiente for Arnaldo!
For Arnaldo! For Arnaldo!
Viva Ardiente!
-Viva Ardiente!
[cheering]
Arnaldo.
Arnaldo, my son.
We've finally won the election.
Isn't this what I promised you?
That I'd make this family rise once more?
And I am going to roll out
the red carpet for when you return.
But you have to help me.
Arnaldo, tell me who did this to you.
Tell me who should pay.
Arnaldo.
Arnaldo, talk to me.
Tell me who should pay.
[tense music playing]
[cocks gun]
Arnaldo.
Talk to me.
Speak.
Please.
Talk to me.
-[groaning]
-[beeping accelerating]
Arnaldo! Arnaldo!
Nurse! Nurse!
-[Ivy] Nurse!
-Arnaldo! Nurse!
[nurse] Excuse me, please.
Please do something, doc.
-Take note of the seizure.
-What's going on, doc?!
Nurse, administer relaxant, 10 cc.
[unsettling music playing]
Hon.
What's happening?
[doctor] It is hard to see
Mayor Ardiente suffer,
but I have to be honest with you.
He may continue to experience
episodes of seizures
due to the abnormal electrical
activity of his brain,
and he may remain in a catatonic state.
It's possible that when
he regains consciousness,
he may not remember anything
about what happened to him
before he got shot,
and this is due to temporary amnesia.
Doc, how long will he stay like this?
It's hard to say.
It might take him months
before he can fully recover
and regain all his memory back.
Please rest assured that
we're doing everything we can
to help him recover immediately.
Please, doc. Please.
-Thank you.
-Excuse me.
[Ivy] At least, Congressman…
At least Arnaldo's awake now.
That's a good sign.
And I have you to thank for that.
I know your visits have
helped his recovery a lot.
-And…
-[exhales deeply]
As soon Arnaldo is fully recovered…
I still want you two to get married.
Thank you.
It's nice to hear that we both
want the same thing to happen.
I don't want you to be
separated from us, Ivy.
You know…
You and I, we make
beautiful music together.
My winning the election proves
that we are the team to contend with.
Because maybe I'm your lucky charm.
Nah.
You're not my lucky charm.
You're the daughter that I never had.
[Ivy exhales deeply]
I'm happy to be part
of your family, Cong--
I'm sorry, you're not
a congressman anymore.
[chuckles]
Governor. Governor Julio Ardiente.
Congratulations. Your new title suits you.
Congratulations, Governor.
I must admit. It has a certain ring to it.
Anyway, my enemies should
start saying their prayers.
Because this is
the beginning of their end.
And I want you to be by my side…
to watch their demise.
Just send the invitation,
and I'll be there.
[ominous music playing]
You can count on it, woman.
You can count on it.
Gentlemen, listen up.
Just because we won the election
doesn't mean the fight is over.
Believe me,
Diego's little group won't stop.
They will all go through
the post-election motions,
starting off with a protest.
But I've got news for them.
I am also declaring war
against the opposition.
Hear me. I don't care how you do it.
Practice zero tolerance whether
it be your wife, your children,
your mother, your mother-in-law,
or your servants in the house.
Do whatever is necessary. Use every means.
But I want to put a stop
to the opposition.
I want all this to end.
Remember this…
the enemies and opponents
of Julio Ardiente…
are the enemies and opponents
of the people of Ardiente.
I can't let Julio Ardiente take office.
We can't. We have to stop his cheating.
His lying to the people.
We can't let this keep happening.
You're right, Lily.
That Julio Ardiente has some nerve.
Diego should be the one taking office.
Dear, we need to oust him
before Arnaldo gets better
and before Julio finds out
that you're Lily.
We'll prove his cheating.
We have a lot of potential evidence.
You're right.
We do have a lot of evidence.
Thank you, Diego.
As long as we don't give up,
there is hope.
I will never accept defeat,
so we will keep fighting.
You will win, Diego.
[dramatic music playing]
-[clapping]
-[woman] People of Ardiente!
Here is Poblacion Ardiente's new
governor, Mr. Julio Ardiente.
[cheering]
[chanting] Ardiente! Ardiente!
[chanting] Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente!
[man shouting] Governor Julio!
[chanting continues]
[cheering]
[supporters whooping and chanting]
[man] We love you!
[cheering continues]
[man] We love you, Governor Julio!
[chanting] Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
-Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
-Viva Ardiente!
Thank you very much.
Please take your seats!
Once again, I would like
to thank all the residents
of the province of Ardiente
who voted for me.
Thank you for giving me
another opportunity
to serve you as your governor.
I promise you…
that I will restore peace
and order in our province.
[cheering]
And I will not bow down
to anyone who ever tries
to hinder the progress
that I dream for the province of Ardiente.
And remember this…
While your Governor Julio
is here to lead you…
there will be no place
for rebels here in our home.
[crowd clapping]
[chanting] Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
-Comrades, wait! Wait!
-[car beeping]
[frantic screaming]
You monster! Are you trying to kill us?!
-Curse those Ardientes!
-Hey!
Are you okay?
Those damn Ardientes! Shame on you!
-Don't move. Don't move.
-Curse those Ardientes!
Hey, let's help him!
-Pandoy!
-Someone call for help! Hurry!
Hang on.
Danny, this is very valuable.
Diego can use this against the Ardientes.
-I understand.
-So, tomorrow…
deliver this to the headquarters.
-Okay.
-[thud]
What's this?
Men, search the house!
-[groans]
-Search the whole house!
You're Ardiente's men, aren't you?
[Fernan] What are you--
-Give that back!
-Take those!
-Hey.
-[groans]
[Divine] Your new clothes look great!
[man] Divine Uytengco.
-[gunshot]
-[screaming]
Help! Help!
Mommy! Mom, no! No! No, please!
Mommy! No! Mommy!
Help, please! Help!
[dramatic music playing]
-[gunshots]
-[screaming]
No!
-[gunshot]
-[groans]
-Viva Ardiente!
[chanting] Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente! Viva Ardiente!
Viva Ardiente!
[chanting] Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
Mr. Diego Torillo, why are you here?
We are here to protest against
Julio Ardiente's proclamation
as governor of this province.
Because aside from harassment
and vote-buying,
cheating also took place
in the last election.
Before the power blackout,
our party was leading.
But they took the lead
when electricity was restored!
What is this?! We are not dumb!
According to our investigation,
the data that was
transferred to the server
did not come from the voting precincts.
It came from an unidentified source.
That's why we're certain that
the Ardientes cheated us.
-Right, everyone?
-That's right!
Mr. Diego, how will you
prove these allegations?
We'll request a preserve order
to determine the real number of voters.
So, Julio Ardiente, I am challenging you.
If you truly didn't cheat, I am
challenging you to a recount
to find out who the people
of this province voted for!
That's right!
[chanting] Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
[chanting continues]
What do you think I ought to do to people
starting riots in my province?
Governor, they're just fighting
for what they think is right.
And I don't see anything wrong with it.
They're like us. They stand
for what they believe in.
I am nothing like those scum.
They are like rats who try
to steal someone else's food.
Do you know what we do
to pests in this province?
[protesters continue chanting]
We annihilate them
before they can become a plague
and run the town into the ground.
[protesters continue chanting]
Sanggano. You know what to do.
Yes, Governor.
-[protesters continue chanting]
-[tense music playing]
Miss Aguas, relax and enjoy the show.
[protesters continue chanting]
[chanting] Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
[chanting continues]
Auntie! Anna! Hide in the back.
Batch, go with them.
Come on.
Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
Stand together!
-[protesters continue chanting]
-[tense music playing]
Hold on!
Friends! Don't let go! Don't let go!
[chanting] Julio Ardiente is a cheater!
-[protesters continue chanting]
-[clamoring]
[protesters continue chanting]
[Diego] Don't let go!
-[protesters continue chanting]
-[tense music playing]
[protesters chanting, clamoring]
-Hold tight!
-Don't let go!
[tense music continues]
[frantic screaming]
[commotion intensifies]
Can you please stop this, Governor?
Miss Aguas, are you not entertained?
[commotion continues]
Forward!
[frantic screaming]
[woman screams]
[shrieking]
-Don't let go!
-Hold on!
Hold tight! Hold tight!
Let me go!
[commotion continues over tense music]
Tell your men to stop this, please!
Who are you to give me orders?
I am Julio Ardiente,
governor of Poblacion Ardiente.
And no one tells me what to do!
Especially not you.
[frantic screaming]
[commotion continues]
Miss Aguas, why are you so upset?
What kind of question is that?
Who wouldn't be?!
Look what you're doing to them!
You have just been elected governor.
You're supposed to work
on winning their support!
Not egging them on!
Your term might end early
if you don't stop this now!
Anna! Auntie Camia! Auntie! Auntie Camia!
[frantic screaming]
[grunts]
[Anna screaming]
[tense music playing]
I have the money.
I am in a position of power.
I have everything I need, Ivy.
I don't need the help of my enemies.
If they want to go against me,
well, they better be prepared
to face the consequences of their actions.
Well then, excuse me.
I'm not in the mood for violence.
[Julio] Wait a minute.
Don't tell me you're acting that way
because you feel sorry for those morons?
Do you really want to know why?
[protesters clamoring]
Let me remind you, Governor,
that I invested a huge sum
in your campaign.
But if your term will end early,
how am I supposed to get back
all that I've put in?
Stop treating me like I'm your enemy
because I'm just looking out for you.
And one more thing, Governor.
You need me more than I need you!
[tense music playing]
[protesters clamoring]
[frantic screaming]
[tense music continues playing]
[music fading]
[somber music playing]
This is precisely why
I could not love you!
Because you're no different
from your treacherous mother!
Get out of my house! Get out! [gunshot]
-Papa!
-Get out!
An Ardiente is not weak.
An Ardiente never loses.
And I will always be an Ardiente.
[ominous music playing]
I will rise up and destroy you all.
Nonsense!
How was Emilia's case whitewashed?!
They got everything.
Who else could've helped Emilia?!
Surprised? I am so back.
-Emilia.
-Hi, Papa.
I've already disowned
that daughter of mine.
[Ivy] Those two are cut from
the same two-faced cloth.
Stay here.
We're attacking Diego's group tonight.
-[gunshots]
-[screaming]
[Ivy] Diego, Julio's men abducted
Anna and your supporters.
They're going to kill them!
-Help!
-Help us!
[theme music playing]